Pranay Kondekar

San Francisco Bay Area • Ph: (408) 417-3665 • E-Mail: pranay.kondekar@gmail.com • Portfolio: http://pranaykondekar.github.io/portfolio/

Objective

To obtain a position in the field of web development where I can enhance my skills and contribute to a positive team environment.

Summary

I am a full stack web application developer. I have over 10 years of professional experience in the field of Internet and multimedia including cloud based solution, tools development, dashboards, e-commerce, Ad Platform, Social Networking and healthcare. In past 10 years I have worked for technology giants including **Yahoo**, **eBay**, **Adobe** and many more.

Following are my strengths:

- An understanding of information architecture of the web.
- Comprehensive knowledge of semantic HTML and HTML5.
- Mastery of CSS and DOM.
- Mastery of JavaScript frameworks including jQuery, YUI and Angular JS.
- Good understanding of developing responsive web design (**RWD**).
- Background in usability and user-centered design.
- A good eye for design.
- Hands on experience with Spring framework including REST/SOAP service integration, handling JSON & XML data.
- Strong knowledge of Web accessibility.
- Working knowledge of Agile and Scrum. Excellent knowledge of Rally and Jira tools used for successful Agile
 implementation.
- Versatile hands-on experience in software development with focus on requirements gathering, product/release/sprint/team
 planning and estimation, design, technical/training documentation, architecture, development, Unit/System/User Acceptance
 testing.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular JS, Bootstrap, Freemarker, Handlebars, jQuery UI, XML, JSON, REST api, Web Accessibility, SEO, Ajax, DOM, Browser Compatibility, Responsive Web Development, Localization, Flex, Actionscript, Spring, Java, Struts, MongoDB, MySql, Node JS, Express JS, Karma, Jasmine, Selenium, Git, SVN, CI

Experience

eBay Inc. – Sr. Front End Developer Consultant

08-2014 to Current

Merchant Integration Platform (MIP) Selling Tool

- Designed a UI for the SFTP-based MIP (Merchant Integration Platform) tool to provide a visual way for sellers to manage their listing feeds
- Developed an onboarding flow to help sellers quickly setup their account to start selling on eBay through MIP
- Designed and developed Configuration Tester tool for sellers who write custom configurations for feed based listing creation.
- Improved the MIP application performance by decoupling services and UI
- Implemented accessibility and localization for MIP https://merchant.ebay.com

Yahoo! - Sr. Front End Developer - Consultant

07-2012 to 08-2013

Working on APT! from Yahoo!, a new advertising management platform designed to significantly simplify the process of buying and selling ads online. APT! will take the pain and complexity out of advertising online by providing an integrated, web-based solution that allows unprecedented ease of cross-selling across a large ecosystem of buyers and sellers. It will allow advertisers to precisely yet easily target audiences while enabling publishers to better monetize their content.

http://www.apt.yahoo.com

Network Level Rate Card - Yahoo! Inc.

In Ad Platform, there are 3 levels at which rate can be decided for ads – Site, Publisher and Network. I worked extensively on creating rate card at Network level, which has capability to override any rate cards set by site or publisher. Also this rate card supports targeted pricing at network level.

I lead User Interface development of this feature.

Inventory Bundling Packages - Yahoo! Inc.

Yahoo! has large inventory of site properties. Not all properties are all time hit and not all properties are prime. Inventory Bundling packages gives a way to sell inventory in bundle. It means – the sales manager can bundle prime and non-prime inventory into package and sell it to the customers as a package by giving impression guarantee.

I lead User Interface development of this feature. This includes the job to get done from 2 more UI developers along with me.

eBay Inc. - UI Solution Architect - Consultant

12-2009 to 06-2012

Cloud - DbaaS (Database as Service) - eBay Inc.

Programming Languages & Technology HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Java, Jersey, REST Web Services.

Project description & responsibilities:

DBaaS serves as part of collaborative goals of OPS self-serviced and SLA-driven infrastructure, platform and application in database domain. It covers entire life-cycle of database request from provisioning, monitoring, migration and decommission.

IET provides DB and storage expertise and coordinates with domain teams (DBA+SAN) and software engineering team to implement DBaaS for mongoDB, Cassandra, MySQL, Oracle.

My Role was lead UI developer – which will facilitate the user to take actions such as Provision DB Cluster, Decommission DB Cluster, View all clusters and maintenance of DB Cluster.

Common Ops Portal- Service Registry - eBay Inc.

Programming Languages & Technology HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Java, Spring, Web Services, Tivoli

Project description & responsibilities:

Common Ops Portal is one stop solution for eBay operation, NOC, Functional Execution Team, PD Users, Product Developers etc. to register the services in the form of Scripts. Because of diverted and large number of teams, it was difficult to track services owned and used by different teams. There were multiple forms of scripts which were performing same task.

Common Ops portal gave one stop solution and removed redundancy to register and execute scripts on any remote machine.

I played role of UI architect in the development of Common Ops Portal.

Sitespeed - eBay Inc.

Programming Languages & Technology Flex, Actionscript, Java, Web Services, AMCharts & Microstrategy

Project description & responsibilities:

Sitespeed is a dashboard used across eBay to monitor loading speed of pages. It's specially made for Network Operations to monitor changes in site loading time. This dashboard represents loading time for worldwide sites (US, UK, DE, FR, IT, Motors) and features (Home Page, Search, View Item, My eBay, and Sign In). This dashboard represents the alerts based on historical data and trends. It's been the ideal example to show large data on limited space. Sitespeed dashboard had been major attraction in Microstrategy World Conference -2010.

I am the sole initiator and developer of Sitespeed dashboard. This dashboard was a challenge, since data used for it comes from Microstrategy. There is no middle layer involved in the development. Dashboard is completely standalone and directly communicates to Microstrategy server to get data.

Data Sources - eBay Inc.

Programming Languages & Technology Flex, Actionscript, Java, Web Services, Cairngorm, and Tivoli.

Project description & responsibilities:

Data sources are the files used in the production eBay environment needed to support application connection settings and parameters for database connections. To give the more secure and also enough info to DBA and NOC while doing the deployment. This tool takes care all Deploy Flows, Emergency Roll back, Stop Changes and the IRC message logging during maintenance of production environment.

I worked on this project in dual role of developer cum System Analyst. I understood existing system, coordinated with developers and end users, provided extraordinary solutions for problems and designed/developed User Interface of Data Sources tool.

Data Center Management System (DCSM) - eBay Inc.

Programming Languages & Technology Flex 4.0, Actionscript, Lombardi, JavaScript, Web Services.

Project description & responsibilities:

DSCM 3.0 consists of two projects:

Core Infrastructure Tool

The objective of this tool is to build the Core Infrastructure component in the ODB (Object Data Browser). The physical components such Floor units (Room, Row, Rack), Power management Unit (UPS, PDU, Panel) and Infrastructure unit (Wiring Plant, Cooling Zone) are represented logically in the ODB as objects through Core Infrastructure Tool

Rack Management Tool

The Objective of this tool is to drive the process of Rack provisioning activity in systematic order involving all the stake holders such as Logistic Group, Datacenter resource allocator(site supervisor), Asset Management group, Site Services, Network Service group.

I worked on this project as a UI Architect. I designed a framework (Workflow Inbox) to accommodate any kind of processes involved in the flow. I used modular approach to distinguish different flows and screens. Screens related to specific process and be attached to Lombardi process and Workflow Inbox renders that screen. Framework and modules(Screens) are developed in Flex 4.0. For this project a library is written to communicate with Lombardi processes.

eGrid

Programming Languages Flex, Actionscript, Java, Web Services

Project description:

eGrid is a framework to accommodate the tools used by eBay Network Operations Center, which includes various dashboards, and site maintenance tools like Mark Up Mark Down, ODB Browse Tree, Data Sources, Config Deployment etc.

Roles and responsibilities:

I am closely working with Network Operation Center (NOC) of eBay, providing them solutions to monitor the ebay sites and keep them alive all the time. I am involved in design and development of monitoring tools and site maintenance tools.

I architected the User Interface Design, created prototypes for the tools to be developed using Adobe Flex, Java, J2EE, html5, CSS, IBM Rational Rose, Web Services and my personal intelligence.

Other Projects with eBay

- Quality Of Service(QoS) Dashboard- eBay Inc.
- · Markup-MarkDown tool
- Expected State Tool

Adobe Systems - Sr. Flex, Livecycle Developer - Consultant

01-2009 to 12-2009

Welcom - World Economic Forum

Welcom is a portal platform for the World Economic Forum members. Its kind of Social Networking Platform where WEF members can access collaborative documents, do the virtual meetings using Adobe Connect, see the user profiles, send contact requests, send messages within welcome users, send messages to external email address, receive messages from external email, get recent updates on the homepage like who logged in, what's going on in the forum etc.

Second main feature of this application is integration of Event management system.

WEF was using Accenture Kiosk platform for managing their Annual Meetings, quarterly meetings in which WEF members meet and discuss on different issues. There are different sessions in the meeting and user has to register for the sessions that he has interest in.

Accenture is having Kiosk platform developed in HTML, Javascript, CSS and Web services as backend communication media. We have migrated the Kiosk functionality into Welcom platform and redesigned everything as a pure flex application.

I worked closely with Adobe Consulting for development of Welcom Platform. I was a part of the development team and played role of Sr. Flex Developer. I worked in all phases of the application right from requirement gathering up to testing. I was responsible for the Kiosk module development, customer interaction; analyze the requirements, code review, load test proof of concept development etc.

Sezmi Corporation – Web Development Intern

09-2008 to 12-2008

Zone Management System

Development of consumer portal RIA for Sezmi Set top box using OpenLaszlo and Java as back-end.

Zone Management System (ZMS) project enables Sezmi Set Top Box users to access their account, create play lists, update play list information, upload resources like videos and pictures. This project is designed for Zone management for Sezmi Set Top Box services, such as advertises, resources, web resources, content providers etc.

Laszlo Systems – Web Development Intern

05-2008 to 09-2008

MyQuest by Care 360 Patient Portal

Laszlo's flagship product Webtop, supports multiple, interoperable applications and services accessible from any browser-enabled device without the need for downloads or plug-ins. End users can access their voicemail, email, address books, calendar, instant or text messages, video conferences, and photos as well as social networking applications from a dynamic, branded web-based environment that senses presence and allows information to follow the user. Information, such as contacts, can be shared across multiple applications to create a unified communications and social networking experience across devices and foster greater brand affinity and deeper levels of customer engagement.

I Worked with Studios team which is responsible for development and customization of Webtop. Webtop is a Laszlo System's Rich Internet Application. I was the critical individual in Webtop's customization and skinning for Rockefeller University, which is one of the Laszlo System's customers. Developed Rich User Interface for Webtop as per customer requirements using OpenLaszlo, JavaScript, CSS and XHTML. I was Involved in Laszlo System's Rich Internet Application Pixamo Photos. This application uses Pixamo photo server. Used OpenLaszlo for UI Development.

I was responsible for provided solution to many OpenLaszlo development issues from OpenLaszlo users such as IBM, GE, FireTrust, CTB etc. Resolved bugs in some of the OpenLaszlo components. I am the lead person in solving OpenLaszlo Application development related issues at Laszlo Systems. I also migrated code from OpenLaszlo 3.4.0 to OpenLaszlo 4.1.0 and prepared training material for the same.

K C Precision - Software Developer

06-2003 to 12-2006

Gauge Block Calibration System software is a complete calibration system where Each slip gauge is subjected to rigorous measurement by a system which gives output in BCD format .System converts BCD into RS232 signals and stores in the database. This data is used for report generation by suitably converting into metric system or imperial system. It also provides facility to see reports remotely using web based approach.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES:

Designing the software models as per requirements, Designing the Database, Developing and testing the application. Provide support to the end users and making the applications easier to use. Debugging the errors in previously developed applications and enhancing those applications.

http://www.kcpindia.com

Education

Master of Science (MS) – Software Engineering San Jose State University, San Jose, CA, USA 01/2007 to 12/2008

Bachelors of Engineering (BE) – Information Technology

07/2000 to 05/2004

Dr. BA Marathwada University, Aurangabad, Maharashtra, India